<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-28T21:26:29-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Amir Asiaee</title><subtitle>Personal website and blog. </subtitle><author><name>Amir Asiaee</name><email>asiaeetaheri.1@osu.edu</email></author><entry><title type="html">Switching to Trello</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/trello/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Switching to Trello" /><published>2018-01-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/trello</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/trello/">&lt;p&gt;I recently gave the Trello another try and was impressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very interested in productivity apps. Every few month, I look around for new trending ones and give them a try for a while most of them fail to impress me, but some find their place in my pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For time tracking, there is no competition, &lt;a href=&quot;https://toggl.com/&quot;&gt;Toggl&lt;/a&gt; has been the winner for a long time, and I don’t see any serious rival on the horizon. For personal to-do lists and task management, I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://ticktick.com&quot;&gt;TickTick&lt;/a&gt; very featureful and user-friendly. Oddly, TickTick is not as well-known as many of its counterparts, e.g., Wunderlist and Todoist. Finally, for project management and online collaboration, I have used Asana for awhile which is very featureful, but somehow I was not happy with the accessibility of the features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;major-lessons&quot;&gt;Major Lessons&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, for collaboration on an over-the-time-zone project, I gave the Trello another try, after my first attempts few users ago. I was impressed with the quality of the phone app and the number of available new features (Power-Ups). So I left the TickTick for my personal use and moved to Trello for to test it for a week, the result was auspicious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general feel of the board&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is very positive. You see a summary of things that need to be done altogether, without scary details and at the same time with one click you can get the gory details of each task. In TickTick you always see all of the other lists and tasks of your current list which is scary and distracting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important feature for me is the possibility of having more than one checklist for each task/card. There are many situations that this feature comes handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also leave comments and chat with the other team members&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; on each card. I use this option to converse with myself! It is helpful in recording the findings, report on performed steps, and explanation of the state that you stopped working on the task for a future resume. It helped me a lot to context switch between different tasks and to resume exactly where I left without wasting a minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, each card description supports MarkDown! I use it to write a final report for the card. For example, if a card is for a meeting, one checklist may be the agenda and people can write their main points as comments and finally, the decision and conclusion can be summarized on top of the card with rich MarkDown formatting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many other features (and Power-Ups) that I want to use and didn’t manage time to try, but even in this state, I’ll cancel my TickTick and join Trello. I hope Trello doesn’t end up like other cool startups turning crippled after the acquisition.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This option is also available in Asana, but Asana (like many other “board simulator” apps) is not built with this philosophy, and I found the board-view of Asana projects less flexible. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This option is also available in Asana. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Trello was acquired by Atlassian in 2017. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Amir Asiaee</name><email>asiaeetaheri.1@osu.edu</email></author><category term="Trello" /><category term="Online Collaboration" /><category term="Project Management" /><category term="To-do List App" /><summary type="html">I recently gave the Trello another try and was impressed.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Miracle of Fresh Eyes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/miracle-fresh-eyes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Miracle of Fresh Eyes" /><published>2018-01-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/miracle-fresh-eyes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/miracle-fresh-eyes/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working on an interesting high dimensional statistics problem &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for which we needed to prove the usual Restricted Eigenvalue (RE) condition and stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;major-lesson&quot;&gt;Major Lesson&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, RE condition helps to prove non-asymptotic consistency of an estimator. Meaning that using the RE condition one can show that for a finite number of samples &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;n&lt;/script&gt; the estimation error of a parameter of interest is upper bounded by some number.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few methods for showing the RE condition among which &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1401.0304&quot;&gt;Mendelson’s small ball method&lt;/a&gt; is very popular. Describing the method needs another post (and actually is not necessary because Joel Tropp has already done a great job explaining it &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1405.1102.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to mention that after stalling over the problem for a while I completely stopped thinking about it and worked on other things for a few weeks and when I re-examined it today (after some context switch warm up) I looked through the problem and quickly saw the answer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main point that I want to share with other knowledge-workers out there is that living with a problem seems desirable and one feels that he makes progress by continually thinking and pursuing a solution but unfortunately, this is not true in many situations for abstract problems. You need to relax or switch to another task for a while and let your  &lt;strong&gt;diffuse mode&lt;/strong&gt;^[3] take over and find a solution in the back of your mind. Then when you come back to the tough problem, you can see with the fresh eyes and hopefully come up with a novel line of attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The paper is almost done, I’ll advertise it after polishing it and uploading it on the arXiv. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;We hope to have an upper bound as a decreasing function of the number of samples &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;n&lt;/script&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Amir Asiaee</name><email>asiaeetaheri.1@osu.edu</email></author><category term="Small Ball Methods" /><summary type="html">I’ve been working on an interesting high dimensional statistics problem 1 for which we needed to prove the usual Restricted Eigenvalue (RE) condition and stuck. The paper is almost done, I’ll advertise it after polishing it and uploading it on the arXiv. &amp;#8617;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Elastic Net: An Intuitive Explanation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/elastic-net-intuition/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Elastic Net: An Intuitive Explanation" /><published>2018-01-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/elastic-net-intuition</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/elastic-net-intuition/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://math.arizona.edu/~hzhang/math574m/Read/elasticnet.pdf&quot;&gt;Elastic net&lt;/a&gt; is a proper tool when we have lots of correlated features in regression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;major-lessons&quot;&gt;Major Lessons&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this scenario, if you apply the vanilla &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lasso_(statistics)&quot;&gt;LASSO&lt;/a&gt; the resulted coefficients are not stable. Instability here means that if you decrease the &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\lambda_t&lt;/script&gt;, the regularization parameter, by &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;t&lt;/script&gt; for each &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\lambda_t&lt;/script&gt; in the path of the LASSO the value of non-zero coefficients can change substantially in any direction (increase/decrease). So depending on the chosen &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\lambda&lt;/script&gt; the value of regression coefficient &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\beta_i&lt;/script&gt; (that determines the importance of the feature &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;X_i&lt;/script&gt; ) can be drastically different and we don’t have any idea of the relative significance of features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a non-degenerate scenario of applying the LASSO, you would hope that after the initial selection of a feature in the LASSO path, its coefficient escapes shrinkage gradually when &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\lambda_t&lt;/script&gt; decreases and reaches the OLS value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such an eventual increase/decrease in selected coefficients does not happen in the &lt;strong&gt;correlated features&lt;/strong&gt; case because those features, arbitrarily divide the importance weight, i.e., coefficients, among themselves while it should be almost uniformly distributed among the correlated dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The uniformness of coefficient over the correlated features can be induced using &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;l_2&lt;/script&gt; penalty (why?). Therefore, elastic net suggests a convex combination of both &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;l_1&lt;/script&gt; and &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;l_2&lt;/script&gt; penalties: &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;% &lt;![CDATA[
\begin{aligned}
        \hat{\beta} &amp;\in \mathop{\mathrm{argmin}}\limits_{\beta} \frac{1}{n} \|\mathbf{y}- \mathbf{X}\beta\|_{2} + \lambda \left[\alpha \|\beta\|_{1} + (1-\alpha) \|\beta\|_{2}^2 \right] 
        \\ 
\end{aligned} %]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the resulted norm ball has sparse facets like &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;l_1&lt;/script&gt;-norm ball while each facet is curved, encouraging equal values for the selected features on that facet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is the elastic-net ball with &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\alpha = 0.7&lt;/script&gt; (left panel) in &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;R^3&lt;/script&gt;, compared to the&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;l_1&lt;/script&gt;-ball (right panel). The curved contours encourage strongly correlated variables to share coefficients. Image is from &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.stanford.edu/~hastie/StatLearnSparsity_files/SLS_corrected_1.4.16.pdf&quot;&gt;Statistical Learning with Sparsity The Lasso and Generalizations.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/elastic-lasso-3d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;elastic-net-ball&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Amir Asiaee</name><email>asiaeetaheri.1@osu.edu</email></author><category term="High Dimensional Statistics" /><category term="Elastic Net" /><summary type="html">Elastic net is a proper tool when we have lots of correlated features in regression.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Staticman vs. Disqus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/staticman-vs-disqus/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Staticman vs. Disqus" /><published>2018-01-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/staticman-vs-disqus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/staticman-vs-disqus/">&lt;p&gt;On several rounds of effort, I tried to use Staticman as the comment manager service for this blog. I failed and finally gave up trying and fall back to Disqus. Here is why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The awesome theme that I’m using is &lt;a href=&quot;https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/&quot;&gt;minimal mistakes&lt;/a&gt; which supports many commenting platform like &lt;a href=&quot;https://staticman.net/&quot;&gt;Staticman&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/&quot;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;major-lessons&quot;&gt;Major Lessons&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer Staticman over all other commenting tools because it keeps the user data where it belongs: on your GitHub repository. Disqus and similar services keep the comments on their servers and (I think for the exact reason) are filtered in some countries like Iran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that I’m using [non-supported Jekyll plugins])/dailyreport/jekyll-scholar/), I have delegated the deploy process to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com/&quot;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt; for the website links to work properly I needed to set the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;url&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config.yml&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://aasiaeet.netlify.com&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this url setup is the main reason that Staticman is not working for me. By default it tries to commit to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{url}\{GitHub username}\repository name&lt;/code&gt; and having the Netlify as the url confuses it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any event, for now, I gave up on Staticman and am content with Disqus. Maybe someday …&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Amir Asiaee</name><email>asiaeetaheri.1@osu.edu</email></author><category term="Staticman" /><category term="Disqus" /><category term="Jekyll" /><summary type="html">On several rounds of effort, I tried to use Staticman as the comment manager service for this blog. I failed and finally gave up trying and fall back to Disqus. Here is why.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gender Pay Gap, Why?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/gender-pay-gap/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gender Pay Gap, Why?" /><published>2018-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/gender-pay-gap</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/gender-pay-gap/">&lt;p&gt;A reason for the gender pay gap and how to avoid it came up in our discussions with early career awardees at the MBI during a seminar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m fortunate to be a postdoc at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mbi.osu.edu/&quot;&gt;MBI&lt;/a&gt; instead of a member of a regular lab. Here, there is a clear agenda for preparing and helping the postdocs to enter the job market. &lt;strong&gt;Professional development seminar&lt;/strong&gt; is an essential part of this preparation process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;major-lessons&quot;&gt;Major Lessons&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the recent seminar, MBI latest &lt;strong&gt;Early career awardees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Pamela Pyzza and Megan Powell shared their experience of getting an academic jab. The discussion was constructive in many ways; an interesting one was the negotiation for the startup fund and all other financial details of the offer, e.g., relocation reimbursement, travel fund, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both awardees were emphasizing on strong early negotiation, and then Megan mentioned something like “it seems that one of the reasons that the gender pay gap exists, is that women are not negotiating tough enough.”. I was delighted to see that this idea has spread around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m following the gender pay gap topic (and all other “(none)equality of outcome” claims) carefully and one of the best explanation that I’ve heard is from Professor &lt;a href=&quot;https://jordanbpeterson.com/&quot;&gt;Jordan B. Peterson&lt;/a&gt;, whom I admire. &lt;br /&gt;
He is explaining the gap as a consequence of women on average being more agreeable than men. (of course this one of the many factors.) Agreeableness is one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Five_personality_traits&quot;&gt;BIG 5&lt;/a&gt; personality traits that are very well-studied in psychology. Men and women (on average) are very different along agreeableness dimension. The evolutionary argument for this is that women have been evolved to care for infants and agreeableness has helped them to climb up their dominance hierarchy. Now that they are fighting their way in the male dominance hierarchy, this trait (at least in this context) is not helpful, and they need to learn to become disagreeable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, JBP had an interview a few days ago on Channel 4 (in the UK) where these ideas came up. The interview gained attention for a certain “Ha! Gotcha!” moment. He stayed rational, consistent, and calm during a heated interview and went offense (to prove a point about the freedom of speech) and made the interviewer speechless for a minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the Youtube video of the interview where he talks about his recent book and answer a wide range of question, including equality of outcome vs. opportunity and the pay gap:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aMcjxSThD54&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cathy Newman, the interviewer, went against the argument of “difference in personality contributes to the pay gap” by proposing that we should make the workplace &lt;strong&gt;less masculine&lt;/strong&gt; to which a Youtuber responded: “The feminist problem with equal treatment is that they are being treated like men.”!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mbi.osu.edu/participate/early-career-award/&quot;&gt;Early career award&lt;/a&gt; is another excellent opportunity provided by MBI. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Amir Asiaee</name><email>asiaeetaheri.1@osu.edu</email></author><category term="Professional Development" /><category term="Jordan B. Peterson" /><summary type="html">A reason for the gender pay gap and how to avoid it came up in our discussions with early career awardees at the MBI during a seminar.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing Jekyll-Scholar</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/jekyll-scholar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing Jekyll-Scholar" /><published>2018-01-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/jekyll-scholar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/jekyll-scholar/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/inukshuk/jekyll-scholar&quot;&gt;Jekyll-Scholar&lt;/a&gt; is formatting references and citations on Jekyll blogs and “formats your bibliographies and reading lists for the web and gives your blog posts citation super-powers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;major-lessons&quot;&gt;Major Lessons&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publication page is necessary for an academic website. Since I’m very lazy, I always wanted to be able to have a single &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.bib&lt;/code&gt; file and a &lt;strong&gt;system&lt;/strong&gt; which generates a webpage from it. Such a pipeline will make it much easier to maintain the website&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll-Scholar is a great plugin for this purpose. I spent sometime during the holidays to customize and integrate it to this website. Here, I some challenges that I needed to overcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-a-non-supported-plugin-on-github&quot;&gt;Using a Non-supported Plugin on GitHub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub is very stringent about the plugins that supported on the GitHub-Pages. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/versions/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the small set of supported plugins which does not include Jekyll-Scholar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to use Jekyll-Scholar you need a third party service, which allows other plugins, to serve your website and deploy it to your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; folder on the master/Github-pages branch of your repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com/&quot;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt; is the most popular and user-friendly tool for &lt;strong&gt;Continuous Deployment&lt;/strong&gt; out there and comparing my experience with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wercker.com/&quot;&gt;Wercker&lt;/a&gt;, I can confirm that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very easy to link your GitHub repository to Netlify and deploy your website with arbitrary plugins. You can refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com/blog/2016/09/29/a-step-by-step-guide-deploying-on-netlify/&quot;&gt;step-by-step&lt;/a&gt; guide on the Netlify website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sorting-publication-by-year-and-topic&quot;&gt;Sorting Publication by Year and Topic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After looking around for options, I found that I either should learn and write some Ruby code for this or I can use Jekyll-Scholar ability to work with multiple &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.bib&lt;/code&gt; files and hack through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t want to spend time learning Ruby, so I ended up copy/pasting BibTex entries to separate files, one for each topic, and read them in inside the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;By Topic&lt;/code&gt; page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- High Dimensional Statistics --&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h3&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;pubyear&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;High Dimensional Statistics&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
{% bibliography -f hds %}

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- Social Network Analysis --&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h3&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;pubyear&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Social Network Analysis&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
{% bibliography -f sna %}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorting by year is simpler because it needs only a single file. I’m borrowing the code partially from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio/blob/master/_pages/publications.md&quot;&gt;al-folio&lt;/a&gt; theme:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
{% for y in page.years %}
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h3&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;id=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;{{y}}&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;pubyear&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;{{y}}&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  {% bibliography -f papers -q @*[year={{y}}]* %}
{% endfor %}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you should put &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;years: [2016, 2015, 2013, 2012]&lt;/code&gt; in the front matter of the related page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;adding-abstract-bibtex-pdf-buttons-for-each-item&quot;&gt;Adding Abstract, BibTex, PDF Buttons for each Item&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_layouts&lt;/code&gt; folder I added the following &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bibtemplate.html&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
---
---
{{reference}}
    {% if entry.abstract %}
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;button&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;btn btnId btnPub--abstract&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;id=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;b_{{key}}-abstract&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;style=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;outline:none;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Abstract&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    {% endif %}

    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;button&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;btn btnId btnPub--BibTex&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;id=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;b_{{key}}-bibtex&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;style=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;outline:none;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;BibTeX&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    
    {% if link %}
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;{{link}}&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;button&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;btn btnId btnPub--download&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;style=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;outline:none; position:relative;white-space: normal;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;PDF&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    {% endif %}
    
    {% if links['sup.pdf'] %}
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;{{links['sup.pdf']}}&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;button&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;btn btnId btnPub--supplement&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;style=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;outline:none; position:relative;white-space: normal;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Supplement&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    {% endif %}

    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;dropDownBibtex&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;id=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;{{key}}-bibtex&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;{{entry.bibtex}}&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/pre&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;dropDownAbstract&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;id=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;{{key}}-abstract&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    {{entry.abstract}}
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And set the Jekyll-Scholar configuration in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; file to work with this layout:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-yml highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;bibliography_template&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;bibtemplate&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll explain different parts of the above file in the following sections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;drop-down-abstract-and-bibtex&quot;&gt;Drop Down Abstract and BibTeX&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to have a drop-down effect for some of the buttons. The mainstream method is to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://getbootstrap.com/2.3.2/&quot;&gt;Twitter’s Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;, but the problem is that I’m using a Jekyll theme which is not supporting the Bootstrap and adding it to the theme just for these two buttons was inefficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I just added the following simple jQuery script in the footer template of the website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;ready&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;str&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;attr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'id'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;.btnId&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;click&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;str&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;attr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'id'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;ret&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;split&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;_&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;ret&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;];&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'#'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;toggle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;providing-pdf-download-link&quot;&gt;Providing PDF Download Link&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jekyll-Scholar can read PDF files from a specific directly fixed in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-yml highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;repository&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;/publications&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;publications&lt;/code&gt; directory should be in the root of your repository. &lt;br /&gt;
Inside of it, you can add files that have the BibTeX keys as their names.&lt;br /&gt;
So &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pubName.pdf&lt;/code&gt; corresponds to a BibTeX entry with the name &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pubName&lt;/code&gt; which is accessible through &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{{ key }}&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bibtemplate.html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;supplement-files&quot;&gt;Supplement Files&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to include supplement, presentation, etc. to your publication entry, you can have your extra file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;publications&lt;/code&gt; folder as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;key.sup.pdf&lt;/code&gt; which is read into &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;links['sup.pdf']&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This is the general philosophy of Jekyll as a static website/blog generator: separating the content from the generation process. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Amir Asiaee</name><email>asiaeetaheri.1@osu.edu</email></author><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="Plugin" /><summary type="html">Jekyll-Scholar is formatting references and citations on Jekyll blogs and “formats your bibliographies and reading lists for the web and gives your blog posts citation super-powers.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Curious Case of Ibrutinib-resistant CLL: Does Reverse-Mutations Exist? - Part I</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/cll-ibrutinib-resistence/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Curious Case of Ibrutinib-resistant CLL: Does Reverse-Mutations Exist? - Part I" /><published>2018-01-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/cll-ibrutinib-resistence</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/cll-ibrutinib-resistence/">&lt;p&gt;The question is, can mutations vanish themselves? We discussed an applied example of CLL treatment with Ibrutinib.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following came up during our lab meeting today with my great postdoc mentor Professor Kevin Coombes. I asked a dumb question like: can mutations reverse during the growth of the cancer tumor? The short answer is no, but instead of that, like always, he came up with an eloquent explanation with a contrived example. I don’t want to repeat him (because those are not my words and therefore I can’t claim that I understood the argument!), so the following with all of its shortcomings is my recall of his argument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;major-lessons&quot;&gt;Major Lessons&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assume a universe with only length one mutation where no deletion, insertion, etc. are possible. In other words, consider only missense/nonsense point mutations. Take the average length of a human gene to be roughly 50 kbp and assume 20000 genes exist. Therefore the probability of a mutation happening in a base pair is &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;10^{-9}&lt;/script&gt;, and this mutation should escape every checkpoints and control mechanisms that prevent such a mutated cell to sustain and proliferate. For simplicity, we ignore the probability of a mutation “escaping through a mesh”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of counter cancer measure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to reverse this mutation, we need a change in the exact same spot on the DNA, and we need to convert it to one of the, say, two neutral SNP allele. Such an event has the probability of &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\frac{1}{4} \times 10^{-18}&lt;/script&gt; which is considered zero in most branches of science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the question is that why in we see some tumor sub-clones which does not have certain mutations. If the whole cancer definition is “accumulation of somatic mutation” and there is no going back after a mutation, then one would expect that all sub-clones have a similar core of mutation tree and only different leaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding to my confusion, Kevin showed us a recent data from CLL patients treated with Ibrutinib&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, a BTK inhibitor, and relapsed. The idea is to store blood samples without sequencing it, and when a patient relapsed go back and sequence the data to see if there is any meaningful predictor for the relapse before the actual detection of the mutation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the history of mutation allele frequency of important genes (BTK and PLCG2), in some patients, we observe odd phenomena. We see a slow rise of those mutations over time and a sharp drop a few month before the actual relapse/resistant diagnosis. It seems PLCG2 mutation was reversing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how should we explain this?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dustingmixon.wordpress.com/2014/02/08/gordons-escape-through-a-mesh-theorem/&quot;&gt;Gordon’s theorem&lt;/a&gt; on a random subspace escaping through a subset of the hypersphere. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;In 2013 Ibrutinib was introduced as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMoa1215637&quot;&gt;targeted treatment&lt;/a&gt; for relapsed/re-factored CLL patients harboring mutations in TP53 or deletion of 17p. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMoa1509388&quot;&gt;Two years later&lt;/a&gt;, it was suggested as an effective first line of attack for CLL. But as Kevin mentioned, I didn’t check, the relapse (and/or drug resistant) rate after treatment is high when the patients pass the two years milestones, and ironically both studied followed up patients for about two years and missed this major issue. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Amir Asiaee</name><email>asiaeetaheri.1@osu.edu</email></author><category term="CLL" /><category term="Cancer" /><category term="Ibrutinib" /><category term="Drug Resistance" /><summary type="html">The question is, can mutations vanish themselves? We discussed an applied example of CLL treatment with Ibrutinib.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Painful Part of Collaboration: Version Control and Shared Storage Spaces</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/gitlab-bitbucket-googledrive/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Painful Part of Collaboration: Version Control and Shared Storage Spaces" /><published>2018-01-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/gitlab-bitbucket-googledrive</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/gitlab-bitbucket-googledrive/">&lt;p&gt;Anyone who had online collaboration experience faced this question one way or another: What is a good version control system for code and manuscripts? Where should we store static data?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;major-lessons&quot;&gt;Major Lessons&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, a version control system is a must-have for an online collaborative project. Putting aside the more classic Sub-version, Git and Mercurial are among the most used version control &lt;strong&gt;softwares&lt;/strong&gt;. Git is supported by GitHub, GitLab, and Bitbucket web interfaces while Mercurial is mostly supported by Bitbucket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the collaboration problem reduces to selecting one of these, right? No! &lt;br /&gt;
Different groups and companies have different preferences, and if you collaborate on the same project with more than one group, there will be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;case-study&quot;&gt;Case Study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our lab ant &lt;a href=&quot;http://cs.umn.edu/&quot;&gt;UMN&lt;/a&gt; we were using Mercurial/Bitbucket, and here at BMI&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; because we are using private (patient) data, we work with an internal version of the GitLab.&lt;br /&gt;
Now, I want to have a joint project with my thesis advisor and my postdoc mentor. What is a good setup?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m fortunate because the software that each group uses is different (Mercurial vs. Git). So the hidden &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.git&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.hg&lt;/code&gt; is considered as a directory in your repository, which you can tell the version control software even to ignore updating. But, I still don’t know how to do this if both parties use, say, Git.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hierarchical-folder-structure-and-reproducibility&quot;&gt;Hierarchical Folder Structure and Reproducibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are using a folder structure proposed for computational biology projects in &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1000424&quot;&gt;a paper&lt;/a&gt; in PLOS Computational Biology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is to keep a clean project folder with as many instruction file and documentation as possible to enable the future researcher to exactly replicate your claim. Roughly speaking, we have a directory for each of code, documentation(paper draft and relevant literature), data(raw and clean), and results (figure, raw experiment outcomes) each of them accompanied with a detail &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;data-files&quot;&gt;Data Files&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another critical issue is the strategy of handling the static files. In any data science project, there are static (input) files. Of course, you do some preprocessing or cleaning, but after that, you usually do not change those files. So, it doesn’t make sense to put those in the repository. They eat up your space, and when you want to commit the software should check all of those for changes (use git or hg ignore for this!). Also, every participant may need to keep large files in different places, e.g., external hard drives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still playing with a standard way of handling this problem. The current approach is as follows:&lt;br /&gt;
Almost every reasonable operating system has an environment variable &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$HOME&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
One can store a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.json&lt;/code&gt; file containing the user defined path to the data folder in the following address:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$HOME/paths/[projectName].json
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;[projectName].json&lt;/code&gt; file will look like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
    &quot;path&quot; : {C:\Users\amira\google drive\[projectName]\data}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of saving files in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;data&lt;/code&gt; folder and pushing all of the clean and raw files in the repository, here only &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;[projectName].json&lt;/code&gt; will be in the repo. And when you set it once to your local data directory, you should put it in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt; list because no one else would need to know where you store your files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;including-google-drive&quot;&gt;Including Google Drive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer to have another backup on cloud for ease of use and possible incidents &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
I have unlimited Drive storage. Google recently changed the name to Backup and Sync and supports instant both way sync.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through trial and error, I’ve come up with the following steps, which prevents Drive’s always syncing feature from ruining your day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quit/Pause Drive and work on your project.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Commit, and push to a remote repository.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open the Drive and let it sync.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’m at &lt;a href=&quot;https://mbi.osu.edu/&quot;&gt;MBI&lt;/a&gt;, my mentor is at &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmi.osu.edu/&quot;&gt;BMI&lt;/a&gt; department! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;You think you can trust version control web interfaces? You are wrong! Read more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/2017/02/01/gitlab-dot-com-database-incident/&quot;&gt;GitLab.com database incident&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Amir Asiaee</name><email>asiaeetaheri.1@osu.edu</email></author><category term="GitLab" /><category term="GitHub" /><category term="Google Drive" /><category term="Version Control" /><summary type="html">Anyone who had online collaboration experience faced this question one way or another: What is a good version control system for code and manuscripts? Where should we store static data?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Indexing with Factors</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/r-factor-indexing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Indexing with Factors" /><published>2018-01-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/r-factor-indexing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/r-factor-indexing/">&lt;p&gt;I spent a cycle figuring out, how R treats factors as an index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;major-lessons&quot;&gt;Major Lessons&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice--warning&quot;&gt;Any non-numeric thing that you read from a data file is going to be a factor, i.e., categorical data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice--danger&quot;&gt;Factors are implemented as numerics/integers in R. So when you use them to index another construct which has row/column name as character you need to do so by &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;as.character()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a typical scenario: You read a column from a file and use it to index some construct. &lt;br /&gt;
You either should read the column as string:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-R highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myDataFrame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;read.csv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;path/to/file.csv&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;stringsAsFactors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;FALSE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or convert the factors using as.character before indexing another construct:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-R highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myDataFrame2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;as.character&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myFactor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Amir Asiaee</name><email>asiaeetaheri.1@osu.edu</email></author><category term="R" /><category term="Factor" /><summary type="html">I spent a cycle figuring out, how R treats factors as an index.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Setting up KaTex for Jekyll</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/KaTex-for-Jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setting up KaTex for Jekyll" /><published>2018-01-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/KaTex%20for%20Jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dailyreport/KaTex-for-Jekyll/">&lt;p&gt;KaTex, the fastest library for displaying math on browsers, gradually increased its supported latex functions and is passing its rival MathJax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was reassured about this when saw the great &lt;a href=&quot;http://erikdemaine.org/&quot;&gt;Erik Demaine’s&lt;/a&gt; active involvement in KaTex’s GitHub community. So I started to set it up for this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to write a few latex math, it is easy to find a way to do it with available resources. For example, if you use KramDown like me, you can choose the MathJax engine and put whatever you want inside a double-dollar sign, and that is about it. But if you may have a math-heavy posts, you should probably go with the KaTex which is not supported in KramDown, and even if you find a way (mentioned below) around it you won’t be able to use your LaTex macro library which will eventually wast your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore for a possible math-heavy posts, you should think about an efficient pipeline. There is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://shuvomoy.github.io/blog/non-technical/2016/01/16/Writing-math-heavy-blogs.html&quot;&gt;suggestion&lt;/a&gt; of using Pandoc to generate HTML from your LaTex source for a Jekyll blog. I’m not satisfied with this solution because I may end up looking at the destination file and modifying things, e.g., adding images &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and I want to use MarkDown for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another idea was to use Pandoc and convert the LaTex file to MarkDown. Here the problem was two-fold. First, my website MarkDown (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;KramDown&lt;/code&gt;) only supports MathJax engine. Secondly, the output MarkDown of Pandoc (known as GitHub Flavored MarkDown) has a single-dollar sign reserved for the in-line math and double ones for equations which is problematic for the KaTex engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering these difficulties and lack of time, I ended up hacking through the obstacles and developed my own “heavy math blogging” pipeline. :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First set the KramDown to work with MathJax engine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-yml highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;markdown&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;kramdown&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;kramdown&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;math_engine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;mathjax&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you need to put the following code in the footer of your website to convert MathJax scripts to KaTex:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- Changing MathJax to KaTex --&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;script[type='math/tex']&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;replaceWith&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;tex&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;katex&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;renderToString&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;tex&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;replace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/%.*/g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;''&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;displayMode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;script[type='math/tex; mode=display']&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;replaceWith&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;tex&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;katex&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;renderToString&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;tex&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;replace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/%.*/g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;''&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;displayMode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now for each math heavy posts you should do the followings: &lt;br /&gt;
1) User your dear LaTex macro file and write your post in TexStudio (or any other editor for that matter). &lt;br /&gt;
2) Use Pandoc to generate a GFM MarkDown file. &lt;br /&gt;
3) Use Notepad++ to record a macro for doing the following:&lt;br /&gt;
  i. Replace &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$$&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  ii. Replace &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$$$$&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$$&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
4) Modify the resulted &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.md&lt;/code&gt; file as needed and publish it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you publish the post, the MathJax scripts will be generated in your HTML file which are replaced with KaTex scripts and the final file gets ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’m not sure how Pandoc handles images, and I don’t want to leave it to Pandoc to decide those formatting decisions when I have a theme and customized CSS style for each element. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Amir Asiaee</name><email>asiaeetaheri.1@osu.edu</email></author><category term="KaTex" /><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="MathJax" /><category term="Pandoc" /><summary type="html">KaTex, the fastest library for displaying math on browsers, gradually increased its supported latex functions and is passing its rival MathJax.</summary></entry></feed>